# **SIMONE ANTHONY**

2904 Summit Lake Dr, Stone Mtn, Georgia 30083-6928 ♦ H: (404) 397-9523 ♦ C: 404-397-9523 ♦

Email: simone.anthony1@yahoo.com ♦ LinkedIn: Simone Anthony

# — Professional Summary ————

With a strong technical skill-set, attention to detail, and 2+ years of experience, My passion and desire is to work professionally as a Full Stack Web Developer, where I can use my technical knowledge to elevate user experience to the next level. I am passionate about web development and thoroughly enjoy learning about new web technologies. I spend much of my free time studying and expanding my professional knowledge.

# SKILLS —

- 1 and a half years of programming knowledge in C/C++.
- 3 years of knowledge of HTML5.
- 3 years of knowledge of CSS3.
- 3 years of programming knowledge in JavaScript (1.5 years of ECMAScript 6).
- 3 years of JQuery.
- 2 years of Bootstrap (Javascript Framework).
- 2 year of PHP experience.
- 2 year of SQL/MYSQL experience.
- 1 year of MAMP experience.
- 1 year experience with Apache server.
- 2 years CMS experience (Expression Engine, WordPress, Magento 1 and Magento 2).
- 1month of Heroku
- Experience with Git, Github and Gitlab.
- GreenSock: GSAP Animation and HTML Animated Banners.
- Experience with MailChimp.
- Experience with Litmus and Email on Acid.

- API Integration into JavaScript (e.g. modernizr, geolocation, Session/Location Storage, google maps).
- Understanding of the windows command prompt/ navigating a computer without a graphical user interface.
- Experience with JSfiddle.
- Strong understanding of web servers, database servers, general networking, protocols, HTTP, FTP, SMTP, POP, IMAP etc.
- Familiarity with Linux and Unix command-line and environment.
- Firm understand of CSS preprocessors (LESS/SASS).
- API Integration into JavaScript (e.g. modernizr, geolocation, Session/Location Storage, google maps).
- Knowledge of photo editing software (e.g. Gimp, Photoshop).
- Full understanding of concepts such as closures,

• Ability to build HTML emails.

object-oriented programming, pointer, references, operator overloading, creating files, arrays, templates, scopes, functions, DOM, BOM, constructor objects, constructor functions and classes. And have used them in practically.

WORK HISTORY

#### Junior Front End Developer, 06/2017 to Current

#### **PureRED** – Stone Mtn, GA

- Developed multiple landing pages using HTML5, CSS3, Javascript and Jquery.
- Built HTML emails
- Utilized Responsive Web Design and Frameworks
- Assisted In building multiple Wordpress sites and helped maintain them for multiple clients.
- Assisted in development of back end features in Laravel (PHP Framework)
- Assisted in developing and adding to PHP Templates used to minimize development time within the workplace.
- Used Basic SQL and MySQL to Inject data Into client Databases
- Built and implemented AJAX MailChimp signup form
- Setup and maintenance of Vagrant environments
- Created and edited Animated Banners using GreenSock (Javascript animation Framework).
- Tested and used Javascript web Audio API.
- Introduced to ES6 and React.

#### Freelance Web Developer, 01/2016 to 05/2016

#### **Self Employed** – Atlanta, Georgia

- Designed, implemented and monitored web pages and sites for continuous improvement in fast-paced environment.
- Introduced to HTML5, CSS3 Javascript and Jquery.

———— REAL WORLD EXPERIENCE	
----------------------------	--

Clients I have worked for:

Purered: https://www.purered.net/

Kings Foods Market: https://kingsfoodmarkets.com/ (frontend)

Balducci's: <a href="http://www.balduccis.com/">http://www.balduccis.com/</a> (frontend)

Arm & Hammer: https://www.armandhammer.com/ (backend)

Xyzal: <a href="https://www.xyzal.com/">https://www.xyzal.com/</a> (frontend and backend)

Nasacort: https://www.nasacort.com/ (frontend and backend)

Dollar General: https://www.dollargeneral.com/ (frontend)

Bevmo: <a href="http://www.bevmo.com/">http://www.bevmo.com/</a> (frontend)

SP Richard: <a href="http://www.sprichards.com/">http://www.sprichards.com/</a> (frontend)

Old Time Pottery: <a href="https://oldtimepottery.com/">https://oldtimepottery.com/</a> (frontend)

Perrin and Rowe: <a href="https://www.perrinandrowe.com/">https://www.perrinandrowe.com/</a> (frontend)

Sears: http://www.searshometownstores.com/ (frontend)

## EDUCATION -

2019

### Certification

Modern React with Redux [2019 Update]

Issued: Aug 2019

Credential ID: UC-RVNO74AF

2016 - Current

## **Real World Experience**

2 year of Front End and Back End Developer Experience

1 year of Freelance Development

Treehouse

Code Academy

Udemy

2011-2015

North Springs High School - Atlanta, GA